{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q2":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The <b>Membership Problem</b> is to determine if a given string belongs to a given language.",
        "question": "If JAVA is the set of all Java programs, what is a Java program?",
        "answer": "A string in the set JAVA",
        "choices": ["A string in the set JAVA", "A set of words", "A set of lines of code"]
      },
      "q3":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "Consider the case where G is a grammar for Java, and $w$ is a Java program. Is $w$ a syntactically correct program? This is (part of) what a compiler does. You write a program, you compile it, and the compiler finds all your syntax mistakes.",
        "question": "The process of compiling the Java source code and determining that the source code is a correct Java program is the same as the membership problem",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q5":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "We have seen that if we can find a derivation from $G$ for $w$, then we know that $w$ is $\\in L(G)$.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G = (\\{S\\}, \\{a, b\\}, S, P),$ $\\quad P = S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b\\ |\\ \\lambda$. What is $L(G)$?",
        "answer": "set of strings with an even number of $a$'s",
        "choices": ["set of strings with an even number of $a$'s", "set of strings with one $b$", "$\\{a^nba^n \\mid n \\ge 0\\}$"]
      },
      "q6":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "We have seen that if we can find a derivation from $G$ for $w$, then we know that $w$ is $\\in L(G)$.",
        "question": "Suppose that $G = (\\{S\\}, \\{a, b\\}, S, P),$ $\\quad P = S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b\\ |\\ \\lambda$. Is $abbab \\in L$?",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q8":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The Exhaustive Search Algorithm is<br/> For all $i = 1, 2, 3, \\ldots$<br/>    Examine all sentential forms yielded by $i$ substitutions.<br/>Suppose that $G = (\\{S\\}, \\{a, b\\}, S, P), \\quad P = S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b\\ |\\ \\lambda$.",
        "question": "We will use the algorithm to see if $abbab \\in L$. Select all sentential forms that result from making one substitution from $S$.",
        "answer": ["$S \\Rightarrow SS$", "$S \\Rightarrow aSa$", "$S \\Rightarrow b$", "$S \\Rightarrow \\lambda$"],
        "choices": ["$S \\Rightarrow SS$", "$S \\Rightarrow aSa$", "$S \\Rightarrow b$", "$S \\Rightarrow \\lambda$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow SSS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow aSaS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow bS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow S$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow aSSa$"]
      },
      "q9":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The Exhaustive Search Algorithm is<br/> For all $i = 1, 2, 3, \\ldots$<br/>    Examine all sentential forms yielded by $i$ substitutions.<br/>Suppose that $G = (\\{S\\}, \\{a, b\\}, S, P), \\quad P = S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b\\ |\\ \\lambda$.",
        "question": "We will use the algorithm to see if $abbab \\in L$. Which sentential forms result from making two substitutions from $S$?",              "answer": ["$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow SSS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow aSaS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow bS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow S$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow SaSa$"],
        "choices": ["$S \\Rightarrow SS$", "$S \\Rightarrow aS$", "$S \\Rightarrow b$", "$S \\Rightarrow \\lambda$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow SSS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow aSaS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow bS$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow S$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow SaSa$", "$S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow aSaaSa$"]
      },
      "q10":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The Exhaustive Search Algorithm is<br/> For all $i = 1, 2, 3, \\ldots$<br/>    Examine all sentential forms yielded by $i$ substitutions.<br/>Suppose that $G = (\\{S\\}, \\{a, b\\}, S, P), \\quad P = S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b\\ |\\ \\lambda$.<br/>The derivation for $abbab$ is:<br/> $S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow aSaS \\Rightarrow aSSaS \\Rightarrow abSaS \\Rightarrow abbaS \\Rightarrow abbab$",
        "question": "How many derivation steps were needed to reach the derivation of $abbab$?",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]
      },
      "q13":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "If the string is in the language, the search algorithm will find it. BUT, What happens if $w$ is not in $L(G)$?<br/><br/>When do we stop the loop in the algorithm and know for sure that $w$ is not going to be derived?",
        "question": "Suppose that $G = (\\{S\\}, \\{a, b\\}, S, P), \\quad P = S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b\\ |\\ \\lambda$. Suppose we have the following sentential form $S \\Rightarrow SS \\Rightarrow ... \\Rightarrow SSSSSSSSSS \\Rightarrow ...$. Substitutions can be made on $SSSSSSSSSS$ to derive $\\lambda$",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": [],
        "correctFeedback": ["This means that we can enter an infinite loop when trying to derive a string."]
      },
      "q16":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem:}$ If CFG $G$ does not contain rules of the form<br/>$A \\rightarrow \\lambda$<br/>$A \\rightarrow B$<br/>where $A,B\\in V$, then we can determine if $w\\in L(G)$ or if $w \\not \\in L(G)$.",
        "question": "Consider the length of the sentential form. If the grammar follows the theorem, then the length of the sentential form will only increase or stay the same every substitution",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q17":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Theorem:}$ If CFG $G$ does not contain rules of the form<br/>$A \\rightarrow \\lambda$<br/>$A \\rightarrow B$<br/>where $A,B\\in V$, then we can determine if $w\\in L(G)$ or if $w \\not \\in L(G)$.",
        "question": "Consider the number of terminal symbols in a sentential form. If the grammar follows the theorem, then the length of the sentential form will only increase or stay the same every substitution",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q18":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Following this theorem, either the length of the sentential form or the number of terminal symbols in the sentential form will increase with each derivation",
        "question": "If $|w| = n$, how many times through the loop will the exhaustive algorithm take to find if the string $w \\in L$ or not?",
        "answer": "$\\le 2n$",
        "choices": ["$\\le 2n$", "$\\ge 2n$", "$2n$", "$n^2$"]
      },
      "q19":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "If $|w| = n$, how many times the loop in the exhaustive algorithm will take to find if the string $w \\in L$ or not?",
        "question": "Thus, if there are $>2|w|$ times through loop, then...",
        "answer": "$w \\not \\in L(G)$",
        "choices": ["$w \\in L(G)$", "$w \\not \\in L(G)$"]
      },
      "q20":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ Let $L_2 = L_1 - \\{\\lambda\\}$. $L_2 = L(G)$ where $G$ is:<br/>$S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aa\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b$",
        "question": "The Grammar does not contain rules of the form<br/>$A \\rightarrow \\lambda$<br/>$A \\rightarrow B$.",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q21":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ Let $L_2 = L_1 - \\{\\lambda\\}$. $L_2 = L(G)$ where $G$ is:<br/>$S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aa\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b$",
        "question": "Let $w = baaba$, is $w \\in L$?",
        "answer": "No",
        "choices": ["No", "Yes"]
      },
      "q22":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ Let $L_2 = L_1 - \\{\\lambda\\}$. $L_2 = L(G)$ where $G$ is:<br/>$S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aa\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b$",
        "question": "With each substitution, either there is at least one more terminal or the length of the sentential form has increased.",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q23":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Example}$ Let $L_2 = L_1 - \\{\\lambda\\}$. $L_2 = L(G)$ where $G$ is:<br/>$S \\rightarrow SS\\ |\\ aa\\ |\\ aSa\\ |\\ b$",
        "question": "How many loop iterations will the exhaustive algorithm need to do to determine that $w \\not \\in L$",
        "answer": "10",
        "choices": ["5", "10", "12", "8"]
      }
    }
  }
}
